- Welcome to our training on B2B apps and APIs.
Amazon Business provides a suite of features
that help optimize business to business or B2B sales.
These include apps that can help you manage
and automate your B2B operations with features
that help with pricing and discounts,
offer product opportunities and delivery options.
Apps are software solutions that connect
with your Seller Central account,
allowing you to perform various tasks
throughout the selling life cycle.
APIs or application program interfaces
are a set of rules and protocols
that allow different software applications
to communicate and interact with each other.
APIs act as point of contact between a client and a server
with the client sending requests
and the server sending responses.
API documentation contains information
on how developers should structure these requests
and responses.
APIs are used to build apps.
For example, your weather app utilizes an API
that communicates with the Weather Bureau's software system
to show you daily weather data.
You have two options for adopting APIs as a seller.
You can use existing public apps with APIs
developed by third party integrators or three PIs
or you can build your own app using our API.
Making your own app may involve hiring a developer
if you do not already have one on your team
in order to create a custom app
to meet your business's needs.
Private apps are built just for your Seller account
so only you can use them.
To develop your own app, go to apps and services
in the Seller Central main menu and click develop apps.
Next, click on the add new app client button,
then enter your app name and choose API type as SP API.
Finally, choose the right roles for your developer profile
and hit save and exit to get the needed data privileges
for your application.
For more information on how to assign roles to a developer
and how to integrate a private app,
watch our video series about selling partner apps
starting with SP API overview on Seller University.
If you intend to use an app across various e-commerce channels
and do not want to build your own,
you can use a public app.
To adopt an existing app,
go to the selling partner app store in Seller Central.
There you'll find a list of public apps
to meet your business's needs
when you filter by Amazon business.
While you can browse and search all the apps we carry
in the selling partner app store,
the best way to view the list of B2B apps
is on the page Amazon Business APIs.
Select B2B from the Seller Central main menu
and click B2B Central.
From here, you'll find B2B API overview in the menu.
Scroll to the bottom of that page
to see the third-party integrators
that have adopted an Amazon business or AB feature.
This section illustrates the AB features included
with each third-party integrated app.
The three PIs are organized by the features available,
like business prices and quantity discounts,
pricing, delivery experience,
multi-location inventory, and package hierarchy.
You can search the heading for the features you're looking for.
If you're looking for an app that includes pricing
or reports and analytics, for instance,
look for three PIs in those sections.
After you identify your selections,
click the name of the three PIs to find out more about it.
Each has a detailed page where you can review its features,
read a description to learn about the intended users,
its pricing, and reviews.
On the right-side menu, you'll find options under functionality
and supported languages.
Note, while we work to keep our information accurate,
click Visit Developer website to go directly to their page
for the most up-to-date information about the app.
Select Authorize Now to start the process
of authorizing the three PIs to access your seller data.
Don't forget to mark the checkbox.
I direct Amazon to provide the three PIs access
to my selling partner account and related data.
I am responsible for any actions taken by the application.
Then, click Sign Up to reach the login page.
To manage your apps once authorized,
go to the Seller Central Main menu
and select Apps and Services.
Then, click Manage Your Apps.
From this page, you can see the list of developers
you've authorized, including their name, ID, app name,
status, authorization date, and MWS authorization token.
Use the Actions column to enable authorization,
reauthorize, disable authorization,
or opt-out of notification.
Thank you, and happy selling in the Amazon store.